Expect the impossible.
Mission: Impossible is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by Brian De Palma.
When Ethan Hunt, the leader of a crack espionage team whose perilous operation has gone awry with no explanation,
discovers that a mole has penetrated the CIA, he's surprised to learn that he's the prime suspect.
To clear his name, Hunt now must ferret out the real double
agent and, in the process, even the score.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
Jim Phelps, played by Jon Voight.
Claire, played by Emmanuelle Béart.
Kittridge, played by Henry Czerny.
Krieger, played by Jean Reno.
Luther, played by Ving Rhames.
Mission: Impossible is a 1996 American spy film directed by Brian De Palma, and produced by and starring Tom
Cruise from a screenplay by David Koepp and Robert Towne and story by Koepp and Steven Zaillian.
A reboot of the 1966 television series of the same name and its 1988 sequel series,
it is the first installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
It also stars Jon Voight, Henry Czerny, Emmanuelle Béart, Jean Reno,
Ving Rhames, Kristin Scott Thomas, and Vanessa Redgrave.
In the film, Ethan Hunt (Cruise) seeks to uncover who framed him for the
murders of most of his Impossible Missions Force (IMF) team.
Numerous efforts by Paramount Pictures to create a film adaptation of the television series stalled until Cruise
founded Cruise/Wagner Productions in 1992 and decided on Mission: Impossible as its inaugural project.
Development initially began with filmmaker Sydney Pollack but most of the final screenplay was completed after De Palma, Steven Zaillian, David
Koepp and Robert Towne were hired; De Palma also designed most of the action sequences, while Cruise did most of his own stunts.
Principal photography began in March 1995 and lasted until that August, with filming locations
including London, Pinewood Studios in England, and Prague (a rarity in Hollywood at the time).
Mission: Impossible was theatrically released in the United
States by Paramount Pictures on May 22, 1996.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for the action sequences, De
Palma's direction and Cruise's performance, but criticism for a convoluted plot.
The film grossed $457.7 million worldwide, making it the third-highest-grossing film of
1996, while the dance rendition of the original theme song by Larry Mullen Jr.
and Adam Clayton became a top-ten hit internationally and was nominated
for the Grammy Award for Best Pop Instrumental Performance.
The film's success led to a long-running film franchise, beginning with
Mission: Impossible 2, released four years later in 2000.
The film explores themes of mask, mission, london, england,
central intelligence agency (cia), computer.
The tone is intense.